Guide to the Anita Arrow Summers Papers, 1925-2018 RL.11815
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Anita Arrow Summers papers
1925-2018
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Summers, Anita A.
RL.11815
0.5 Linear Feet One box.
Anite Arrow Summers (born 1925) is a Senior Research Fellow at the Sell-Lurie Real Estate Center and Professor Emerita of Public Policy and Management at the University of Pennsylvania. This collection primarily documents her professional life and family connections to other notable economists. It was acquired as part of the Economists' Papers Archive.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Anita Arrow Summers papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library as a gift from Summers in 2019.
Arrangement
The Anita Arrow Summers papers are arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Anita Arrow Summers (born 1925) is a white American academic and government economist. She earned an AB in economics from Hunter College in 1945, an MA in economics from the University of Chicago in 1947, and undertook doctoral studies at Columbia University. She worked as Head of the Urban Section in the Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia's Research Department, and in various capacities at the University of Pennsylvania. She is currently a Senior Research Fellow at the Sell-Lurie Real Estate Center at the Wharton School at the University of Pennsylvania, and Professor Emerita of Public Policy and Management at Wharton. She served as a member of the Board of Directors of Meridian Bancorp, Inc., Merit Mutual Savings Funds, Advancted Technology Center, William Penn Foundation, Executive Services Corps, and as Chair of the Board of Directors of Mathematica, Inc. She is currently a member of the Board of Directors of Waverly Heights, Ltd.
Summers has notable family ties to other prominent economists. Her brother is Kenneth J. Arrow. Her husband, Robert Summers, is a noted economist and the brother of Paul A. Samuelson. Anita Summers's son is economist Lawrence H. Summers.
Related Materials
Robert Summers papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Kenneth J. Arrow papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Paul A. Samuelson papers, David M. Rubenstein Rare Book and Manuscript Library, Duke University.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents Summers' career as an economist. It provides a sample of her professional activities, particularly her research on urban economics, education and economics, and the local economy in Philadelphia.
The collection also documents her familial ties to other prominent economists, such as her husband Robert Summers, her brother Kenneth J. Arrow, and her brother-in-law (via Robert) Paul A. Samuelson.
Education -- Economic aspects; Economists -- United States -- Correspondence; Pennsylvania -- Economic conditions; Public policy; Urban economics; Women economists -- United States; Arrow, Kenneth J. (Kenneth Joseph), 1921-2017; Economists' Papers Archive; Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia. Research Department; Mathematica, Inc.; Samuelson, Paul A. (Paul Anthony), 1915-2009; Summers, Anita A.; Summers, Lawrence H.; Summers, Robert, 1922-2012; Wharton School -- Faculty
- Arrow, "Effects of the Price System and Market on Urban Economic Development", 1970 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes reprint of article written by Kenneth Arrow.
- Article Clippings, 1987 (Box 1)
  Includes copies of newspaper clippings on the economy in Philadelphia.
- Awards and Honorary Degrees, 1995; 2011 (Box 1)
  Includes a citation from the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania and an honorary doctorate from Hunter College.
- Clippings, 1986-2017 (Box 1)
  Includes copies of newspaper and other clippings referring to Anita Summers and her work.
- CV, 2018 (Box 1)
  Includes a copy of Summers's CV.
- Do Schools Make a Difference?, 1977 (Box 1)
  Reprint of article written by Summers.
- Family Materials: Kenneth Arrow, 1925-2017 (Box 1)
  Includes family photos of Summers's brother, Kenneth Arrow, and copies of speeches given by Summers in memory of Arrow.
- Family Materials: Paul Samuelson, 1933-1994 (Box 1)
  Includes family photographs, copies of talks given by Sameulson, and brief correspondence with Samuelson (Summers's brother-in-law).
- Fiscal Stance of Philadelphia, 1976 (Box 1)
  Includes copy of an article written by Summers.
- Improving the Use of Empirical Research as a Policy Tool: An Application to Education, 1979 (Box 1)
  Includes copy of briefing paper by Summers.
- Inflation and the Philadelphia Economy, 1981 (Box 1)
  Includes copy of article written by Summers.
- Mathematica, 2013 (Box 1)
  Includes copy of speech on the history of Mathematica, Inc. given by Summers in her capacity as Chair of Board of Directors.
- Notebooks from Viner's Class, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  Includes notesbook from classes Summers took with Jacob Viner at the University of Chicago.
- Philadelphia Metropolitan Case Study, 2000 (Box 1)
  Includes a draft paper by Summers.
- Philadelphia's School Resources and the Disadvantaged, 1974 (Box 1)
  Includes copy of paper written by Summers.
- Proposition 13 and its Aftermath, 1979 (Box 1)
- Urban Change in the United States and Western Europe, 1999 (Box 1)
  Includes copy of book edited by Summers.